Welcome to the Community Event Planner. Every number on screen comes from a Postgres view generated from one rulebook.
Header-based login with four dev roles. We'll pick Admin so we can show the edit flow later.
The dashboard. Four stat boxes — each an aggregation over the Events table: total, ready to publish, attendees, and events with issues.
Below, four upcoming events. Each row shows speakers, attendees, seats left, and a calculated status. Yellow flags mark venue conflicts.
Now the interesting part. I turn on provenance mode. Every derived value gets a function glyph showing it was computed, not stored.
Clicking 'Ready to Publish' opens the explainer for Events dot EventStatus. The formula is an IF over HasSpeakers, AtCapacity, and HasVenueConflict — three sub-calculations with their own DAGs.
Back, then 'Total Attendees'. This opens BookedCapacity — a COUNTIFS aggregation over RSVPs filtered to confirmed status.
Back to the dashboard. Provenance off, and into tech-talk-1.
The Event Status block breaks the status into a checklist: speakers, capacity, venue conflicts. Every check or X is itself a calculated field.
Further down, Registration. Deadline and Open or Closed are both calculated from the close-days setting and the current time.
As admin I get a pencil to edit. The form changes raw inputs — name, venue, date, duration, close window, category.
Watch this: I change Registration Closes from one day to thirty days before. One raw field, RegistrationCloseDaysBeforeEvent.
Save fires a PATCH. The view recomputes. UI updates — no frontend math.
Now the Speakers tab — a calculated view over the Speakers table.
Each speaker shows an AssignmentCount aggregation. If anyone went over three, the page would surface an Overbooked warning at the top.
Last hop: clicking AssignmentCount opens its DAG — an aggregation over Assignments. Every number you saw came from the rulebook.